

Slava Kuznetsov, PhD, PMP

Novi Sad, Serbia

Email: cv@pmslava.com
Web: pmslava.com

Summary of Qualifications

17 years of Project Management: Methodologies (Agile, Scrum, Waterfall), Project management offices and project offices (PMO, PO), Projects, programs and portfolio management (PM, PgM, PfM)

Software Innovator: Development and implementation (Expo, Marketplace, CRM, SCM, WMS, PMS, SharePoint)

Business Analyst: Business processes optimization (IDEF, ARIS, BPMN, MindMap, MS Visio), Efficiency development (KPI, KRI, BSC, SWOT), Audit of processes (ISO 9001, Part-145, PMBoK)

Associate Professor in Economics: Lectures, seminars, trainings, research works, publications

Professional Experience

Product owner, LeadFrog 2021 - 2023

I am responsible for developing a product that will compete against well-established solutions in the market. In my role, I communicate with investors, clients, technical directors, analysts, designers, marketers, sellers, and team leaders. I'm involved in all stages of the product development process, from market research and MVP development to technical support and user experience study.

LeadFrog demo website.

Chief project management officer, Ostec Group

2013 - 2020

Main achievements:

- 55 successfully implemented investment projects through Project Management Office;
- 350 developed and implemented design specification in 1C;
- A 10-fold reduction of non-targeted investments;
- Training about the basics of project management for 150 employees.

Key projects:

- <u>EcbMarket</u>: Marketplace for manufacturers and consumers of electronic components (custom search and navigation, seller listings, admin and user interfaces, social connect, messaging and notifications, mobile friendliness, analytics dashboards, user support);
- Supply management system (1C:SCM), including ability to plan activity from logistical statuses, partial repayment of payments and integration with the warehouse system;
- Corporate Internet portal with support for social functions and benefits;
- Project management system with design and management of project management office.

Head of process management and development, Volga-Dnepr Group

2010 - 2013

Main achievements:

- 50 formalized procedures;
- Developed the balanced scorecard BSC for 10 directions;
- Incorporated into the program of key personnel reserve.

Key projects:

- Risk management system (risk classification, safety policy, committees and department design);
- Balanced scorecard, integration with motivational schemes;
- Planning and control system for annual tasks of departments;
- Business-process model of company together with Boeing consultants.

Leading consultant, BDO Unicon

2008 - 2010

Main achievements:

- Implementation of major projects, for more than 2 million dollars;
- 5 out of 5 according to grade given by 360 degree rating, 100% time utilization.

Key projects:

 Program to improve corporate management of Gazprom Germany Group, analysis of external environment and competitors, SWOT analysis, optimization of gas realization schemes;

- Monitoring of effectiveness and risks for activity of OJSC Gazprom long-term financial investments, including development and implementation of KPI and risks KRI;
- Conception of project management system for Uranium Holding.

Associate professor, MAI University

2006 - 2010

Main achievements:

- 4 author's courses: project management, economics of enterprise, organization and planning of production at the enterprise, crisis management;
- Training of 150 students per year;
- Teaching 7 different economical courses.

Key projects:

- Design of managing program for development of short-medium-haul aircraft;
- Development of methodology and evaluation of effectiveness of use of industrial real estate.

Consultant, Project Practice Group

2005 - 2008

Main achievements:

- 4 projects simultaneously due to high working capacity;
- Communication with representatives of 5 large customers: the Ministry of Health, the government of Federal district KhMAO, the Federal Protection Service, the Ministry of agriculture, Irkut Corporation.

Key projects:

- Designing monitoring systems for state programs and priority national projects basing on MS Project Server;
- Production of corporate systems for managing projects.

Education

English Advanced (IELTS 8.0), British Council, 2021

PhD in Economics (Project management in Aviation holding), MAI University, 2011

Project Management Professional (PMP Certificate), PMI, 2009, 2019

Master of Economics and Management (Honours degree), MAI University, 2006

Advanced Training

20+ courses from 2006 to p.t. with certificates: IBM Jira, Data Scientist, Software Development, Risk Management in Developing Projects, Agile, Kanban, Scrum, IT-analytics and administration in 1C:ERP+PM, Programming framework in 1C, Platform 1C: Enterprise 8.2, Time management, Quality and efficiency of processes, Quality audit according to Part-145, Human factor according to Part-66, Requirements EASA Part-145, Strategy development, Project management, Business planning, Portfolios and programs, Requirements PMBoK, MS Project

Key Skills

Product creation, MVP, SaaS, Project management, PMP, PMO, Agile, Software development, Economics, Operational management, PMBoK, MS Project, MS SharePoint, 1C:ERP+PM, Business plans, Audit, Re-engineering, Business processes, KPI, KRI, BSC, ISO 9001, Part-145, GDPR, MS Visio, ARIS, Technical requirements, Software design, Redmine, Jira, Customer support, Staff training, Linux, FOSS.